Harry Turnbull

Twitter: @hturnbull | Email: hturnbull@live.co.uk | GitHub: github.com/hturnbull93 | Blog: medium.com/@hturnbull93

I am a Full Stack developer, looking for new opportunities to continue to learn, challenge myself, and work with great people to build amazing things.

I trained at Makers Academy (London's leading programming bootcamp), to learn best practices, tools and methodologies, which led me to my Full Stack position at AppScore Technology Ltd.

While I've learned much at AppScore, the team is quite small, and I'd like to be able to work with and learn from more experienced developers to expand my skills and knowledge of best practices.

Skills

Agile Project Organisation - At AppScore I championed the use of agile methodologies. Previously the team had little structure in place in terms of creating tickets and planning developments. I introduced more stringent requirements for tickets to be considered ready for development and completed. This has led to an improvement in our ability to estimate work and affect positive development workflow changes in response to retrospective sessions.

Team-Focused - The team is only as strong as its members. I mentor a junior developer through group planning sessions, pairing on tickets, and code review. As part of the agile methodology described above, we mob on problems to unblock team members as quickly as possible.

Communication - When communicating with non-technical stakeholders, translating technical details to and from less technical terms is key. Additionally, I have successfully used my ability to communicate, and my experience of UX/UI design, to persuade clients away from features that would annoy users.

I believe the best way to know if you truly understand something is to communicate it clearly to someone else. With that in mind I maintain a Medium blog of things I learn and want to share my understanding of.

Technical Knowledge - I have worked with a variety of languages, technologies and softwares:

Languages JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Ruby, Python

Technologies Node.js, React, Apollo GraphQL, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL,

Docker, Linux, Git

Testing Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Cypress, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai,

Sinon,

Concepts XP/Agile methodology, TDD/BDD, Object Oriented Design, Remote

working, Pair programming, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Git

workflow, Code review, MVC Pattern, GraphQL and RESTful APIs

Hobbies and Interests

Improvised comedy - I perform live on stage with no script, based on audience suggestion. Skills from improv have great applications in the workplace too, such as active listening, generating ideas, building trust within teams, and working out of joy instead of fear.

Cycling - I enjoy cycling, especially e-bikes.

Running - I run to keep fit, and sometimes I enjoy it.

Projects

Spreddit - A reddit clone.

Mission-Ctrl - Group project. An arcade style game to learn VSCode shortcuts.

Bank Tech Test - A CLI program emulating a bank account, showcasing test driven development in 3 languages.

Neogram - A social media photo sharing web-app, inspired by instagram and neomorphism design.

News Summary - A single page web app consuming the Guardian API, using vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS.

Experience

AppScore Technology Ltd (July 2017 to Present) *Full Stack Developer*

The Nursery Theatre Ltd (Nov 2017 to July 2020) *Digital Communication and Website Manager*

Graphic and Web Designer (Aug 2017 to Present)

Freelance

Freedom Tech Ltd (Nov 2015 to Jul 2017) Marketing and Project Manager

Education

Makers Academy (Feb 2020 to Jun 2020) A 16 week intensive programming bootcamp

FreeCodeCamp (2018 - Present) Responsive Web Design Certification

University of Nottingham (Sep 2011 to Jun 2015) MSci Life Sciences, 2:1